[A Moment But Forever]
[Episode 32]
Your eyes
are just temporary blind.
When I was at Tianqu Peak,
I could only see
a small patch
of the sky when I looked up.
At that time, I thought
that after I got out,
I had to take a good look at the stars.
I didn't expect
that when I really got out,
I didn't feel like
stargazing anymore.
Look over there.
It's the Maiden constellation.
It's shaped like a basket
and looks like the character "woman."
And there.
Those five are the Lizhu constellation.
Its appearance
is like a backward bowl.
♫Listening♫
♫Toona leaves knock fireflies into a vase♫
♫Ripples faintly spreading♫
♫In the pavilion in the clouds♫
♫Warm wine brews to the sound of the zither♫
♫The fragrance lingers like brush strokes, sketching out your form♫
♫Tonight♫
♫In a light intoxication, I feel the longing in the crystalline snow♫
♫I cannot bear to think of you♫
♫I only wish♫
♫That the years would remain ever sunny♫
♫So that, within the drifting light, I could share the breeze with you♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It stirs the scenery♫
♫It awakens our heart♫
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
♫The closer we get♫
I wish time
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
can stop at this moment.
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It stirs the scenery♫
♫It awakens our heart♫
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
♫The closer we get♫
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
There's a shabby temple ahead.
We can rest there.
You're tired?
Zhi Dai, are you tired?
Even if you're not, the horse is.
I know you are anxious.
I am too.
Please listen advice occasionally,
Young Master Tanghua.
How can we search when we're all tired?
Let's go.
Embroidery God Temple?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's safe here.
I'll find some hay to feed the horses.
Zhi Dai.
You look a little dazed.
Are you tired?
A bit.
It's my fault.
I was busy searching
and forgot your cultivation.
It's time to rest.
Here.
Good. This mat can be used.
Although it's a bit shabby,
it's better than nothing.
Zhi Dai,
take a rest.
I’ll go hunt some wild game.
I’ll tell Qian Lin
not to disturb you.
Have a good rest.
Okay.
It's been years.
How does it feel to be young?
Goddess of Embroidery.
You still remember me? Not bad.
You've helped me a lot.
All these years,
I've prayed and worshipped you.
I never dared to forget, even for one day.
That's good.
Do you remember
what I told you
when you begged me
to give you youth?
I told you,
"A god won't bestow blessings
upon a useless person.
Instead of kneeling down to me,
why don't you make a deal with me?"
Now,
it's time for you
to complete the deal.
You can see now?
You can see now,
right, Yuanzhong?
Maybe I've recovered.
Great.
Can you leave now?
I'll pack your luggage.
Do you really want us to leave?
No.
Didn't you say that you only came
to recuperate
and will leave after he's recovered?
Yuanzhong not only has an eye injury,
but also a knife injury.
He's still injured.
A knife injury?
You got quite a lot of injuries.
Yes.
So, we might need to
trouble you for a while longer.
Fine.
I'm not an unreasonable person.
You're injured.
Take a good rest.
Yuanzhong's injury
needs some more time
to recover.
Now that the celestial ladder has been destroyed,
and the Ascension Platform was sealed,
the only passage between the human and deity realms
is the Sea of Flux.
That's a place beyond the boundaries.
It's extremely dangerous.
Now that I've lost my divine bone,
it's even harder.
I need a perfect plan.
Spatial Spell!
Juanjuan?
Juanjuan.
There's no one in the room.
No one?
What a pity.
I made a table of delicious dishes,
but there's no one to eat it.
What delicious dishes?
Let me see.
Wasn't there no one here?
Now there is one,
okay?
It's so delicious.
How can you
cook so well?
Eat slowly.
Have some water.
A little.
Your craftsmanship is so good.
I didn't expect you
to be so good at cooking too.
I thought
your cooking skills
are similar to mine.
I used to be at your level,
but
to become
Yuanzhong's handmaiden,
I trained hard for a long time.
I really don't understand
what you see in Yuanzhong.
I cook so well.
Do you want to learn from me?
Otherwise, when I leave,
you won't be able to
have so much delicious food.
But cooking is too troublesome.
It's not difficult at all.
You
cook to please Yuanzhong.
I don't have anyone to please.
What about pleasing yourself?
Forget it. I'll just be lazy.
Then,
do you want to learn craftsmanship from me?
I'm not bragging,
but my craftsmanship is the best in the three realms.
The best in the world.
Many people want me
to be their teacher.
But
I think you're very smart.
Why don't I take you as my disciple?
How about I teach you
all my amazing skills?
Do you need my help?
Just say it.
What is it?
Then I'll get straight to the point.
Go ahead.
Your Barrier Spell
is magic created with the rules
of heaven and earth.
So you came for this?
Yes.
Are you interested?
Actually, I've learned
some spatial rules.
And through craftsmanship,
I've also grasped
how to change the size of space.
But now,
I need to go somewhere.
The environment there is extremely dangerous.
If I only have my knowledge of space,
I'm afraid it's not enough to pass.
So I want to learn
your Barrier Spell
to divide space
and reject external objects.
I see.
But it's complicated.
Actually, the Barrier Spell,
put bluntly,
is just the method of space separation.
Everything is intertwined.
Even the laws of heaven and earth
are intertwined.
In fact, everywhere visible
to the naked eye
has undetectable spatial cracks
everywhere and at all times.
Is that so?
I think even
the dangerous place you mentioned
is the same.
Again.
It's almost done.
Don't mind it. Try again. Hurry.
Okay.
It's done!
Ji Tanyin, you did it!
How did you do it?
Try again.
Let me see.
Sure.
Awesome!
You're amazing!
Do you know
how long I practiced this?
I can't believe you
learned it immediately.
It's nothing.
No.
I just told you
my own understanding.
You learned so much
on your own.
I don't even know this.
You're…
You're just...
What's wrong?
The moon!
It's midnight.
What's wrong with the moon?
What's wrong? This is a huge problem!
I usually sleep
before midnight.
I've kept this habit for 10 years.
No, no.
I have to go to bed now.
Ji Tanyin,
goodbye.
Let's practice tomorrow.
Bye.
Time to go.
Still reading?
Eat something first.
I just made it.
Eat it while it's hot.
Okay.
The weather is nice today.
After dinner,
come take a walk.
It'll help you recover.
I picked it this morning.
It's fresh. Try it.
I think you should be
mostly recovered.
If you're almost recovered,
I plan on…
I plan on leaving.
How do you feel?
How did this happen?
Why is it getting worse?
Yes.
How long has it been?
It shouldn't be bleeding anymore.
Yuanzhong.
Did you move around again
and hurt your injury?
Why are you glaring at me?
I'm just caring for you.
Yuanzhong was hurt by the God-Slaying Dagger.
I had experienced this
when in the Demon Warriors’ hands.
I could feel an extremely strong
malicious aura on the blade.
Malicious aura?
Ordinary weapons
won't hurt Yuanzhong.
Thank you.
My injuries
hinder you.
I'm sorry.
Don't say sorry.
I should stay with you.
By the way,
where are you going?
How about
I go with you
after I'm better?
You should recuperate first.
No, I have a question.
Why
don't we get rid of the malicious aura
before healing the injury?
Do you have
medicine to remove the malicious aura?
Of course.
The War Demons' techniques
carry malice.
I hid a lot of
malice-removing medicine
before coming to live in seclusion.
This is the Vermillion Fruit.
It grows in the extremely hot region in the south
and feeds on the power of geothermal fire.
It is the natural enemy of malicious aura.
Can I eat this directly?
No.
You need to peel it
and separate the skin from the flesh.
Then boil it in water
for four hours
and smoke it.
After it dries, grind it into powder and mix with water.
Finally, you can consume it.
By the way,
everyone in the Youhu Clan
knows this method of countering malicious aura.
Didn't Yuanzhong tell you?
He probably forgot.
I think the water is boiling.
Should we
peel it first?
Yes.
After peeling, steaming, drying,
we'll grind it.
Then did we
boil the water
too soon?
It's okay.
It's warmer here if we boil the water.
Well,
let me peel it with you.
Sure.
I can't even choose the right time
to boil water.
Am I stupid?
No.
Everyone has things
we are not good at.
But I think
there's nothing
I'm good at,
Look.
Isn't creating medicine
something you are good at?
But I read it from books.
It's good
to like reading.
When I went to your room last time,
I saw you had
many good books.
Yuanzhong likes reading too.
When I was in the Liujiao Palace,
he always had a book in his hand.
Even now,
he can read
for a long time once he starts.
No matter what happens,
as long as there's a book,
he seems to be able to settle down.
I think
there are two kinds of people in this world.
One is
the type who likes to read quietly.
The other type
likes running around.
These aren't the only two types.
What about you?
Which type are you?
I used to like reading.
But later,
somehow,
I kept running around.
Maybe
I fell in love with running around.
You're going to run around again,
right?
I won't run around.
I'm leaving.
I have my own matter
to handle.
If you leave,
Yuanzhong will be very sad.
I'll be back.
They all say so.
When people leave,
they always say
they'll come back.
But after they leave,
they never come back.
Some goodbyes
eventually turn permanent.
When the Youhu Clan and War Demons
were at war,
my family and friends
were all like this.
They never came back.
My family and friends
were Yuanzhong's family and friends.
What kind of person
was Yuanzhong?
Him?
When he was little,
he was very annoying.
So naughty
and mischievous.
He liked to prank people too.
He was the biggest troublemaker
in the whole mountain.
So noisy!
But then,
he got the Divine Left Hand,
so…
So what?
He became
even more annoying.
He was arrogant.
He thought he was great.
And after that,
he was sealed
and he changed completely.
Changed?
He became like a mannequin.
Did you see him later?
He said
you left after the two clans
declared war.
Actually,
I went back once.
But
I thought everyone had changed.
They'd become strangers,
so I left again.
But
this time,
I see you two together
and I think he's changed again.
He seems to have turned back
into the
annoying person.
But no matter what,
it's much better than that mannequin.
So,
don't let him
turn back into that mannequin again,
okay?
Have some medicine.
I'm leaving for a while.
I wanted to wait
until you recovered,
but it's been delayed too long.
There's no time.
Everything is fine here.
It's safe.
You can stay here
to recuperate in peace.
Juanjuan will also...
Where are you going?
I'm going home.
Something happened at home.
But it's fine.
Fortunately, some respected elders
of the clan are there.
With them there,
they will be fine.
As long as they think of
a solution,
it will be solved.
You need to wait for me.
Can't you be like before?
What?
Just like before
when you pretended to die,
without moving or speaking,
without a breath or pulse,
without consciousness,
and wake up after a while.
Can't you do that?
You promised me
you'll always be with me.
Does it still count?
Of course.
Then why are you leaving?
I'm just leaving for a while.
How long is "a while"?
Where are you going?
Where is your home?
Did something happen to you?
If you don't come back,
where can I find you?
If you are in danger,
how can I help you?
How long
must I wait for?
How long before you're back?
You want me to wait,
but do you know
how it feels
to wait for someone?
♫Going through thousands of years♫
Didn't you promise me
to be with me forever?
♫In exchange for a dreamlike love♫
To grow old with me,
until my hair grays,
my teeth fall out,
and I'm surrounded by descendants,
♫If the wind is all yours♫
living a peaceful and stable life?
♫No bitterness in your expression♫
What?
♫Everyone comes without a match♫
Are you going back on your word?
No.
♫Why are they willing to be gentle?♫
Then don't go anywhere.
Stay here with me.
♫The moment your image appeared in my eyes♫
♫The answer appeared♫
♫But time♫
I can't.
You can't?
♫Always hides the waves and smoke♫
♫Under the clouds, the good days♫
Why not?
Why can't you?
♫Come and go in a flash♫
♫Like the wind and moon, I'm filled with love♫
♫But it makes people go to the end of the world♫
♫Willingly going through dawn and dusk♫
♫To embrace you and listen to the rain♫
♫Only then can I know what is memorable♫
♫When I can only look back at you♫
♫If there's still a way to continue♫
♫I'll go no matter what♫
♫Like the wind and moon, I'm filled with love♫
Let's get married.
♫But it makes people go to the end of the world♫
Marry me.
♫Willingly going through dawn and dusk♫
Pray in front of the gods
♫To embrace you and listen to the rain♫
and say you're willing.
to be my wife.
♫Only then can I know what is memorable♫
Then...
♫When I can only look back at you♫
I'll let you go.
♫If there's still a way to continue♫
♫I'll go no matter what♫
What should we do now?
Travel by water or land?
We'll know after asking.
Even though a tortoise lives long, its time still runs out.
It's the same with the enchantment technique.
It's almost time.
You're getting old again.
Aren't you afraid?
Besides,
even if you don't think for yourself,
you should think for your people.
You're now the City Lord of Yandu City.
You don't want them
to be punished
because you deceived the gods, right?
City Lord Dai,
a wise person submits to fate.
Do what I told you.
Zhi Dai.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
A man
about this tall.
The woman is very thin.
A man and a woman.
Let me guess.
Were they driving a carriage?
Such clear description.
Have you seen the people we're looking for?
You think too much.
Haven't seen them.
No?
Then why do you know it so well?
How can I not know?
Are you kids
going to kill the demons too?
How do you know
we're going to kill demons?
You look smart.
Why do you always ask silly questions?
If you were me
and a dozen of people asked you every day,
you'd know everything too.
You people
just won't live a peaceful life.
If you have time,
why can't you spend it
doing something useful?
Today, you slaughter demons.
Tomorrow, you kill gods.
Do you know that civilians
can barely afford
to eat fish anymore?
Let's go.
He doesn't know anything.
Let's try our luck and take the waterway.
Take the land route.
I know where to find them.
[Serenity]
I noticed you didn't
eat much at dinner.
I made some porridge.
Do you want to try it?
Are you mad at me?
No.
Tanyin,
has anyone told you before
that you are
really bad at lying?
How unlucky.
You met me.
I'm the best liar
in this world.
In the future,
you will be completely fooled by me.
Don't say that.
Fine.
I swear to the heavens that
I, Yuanzhong, will never
lie to you again.
If I break this oath,
let my divine soul perish
and never be reincarnated.
Don't say that!
Don't blame me.
Don't be mad at me
and don't ignore me.
I know
I shouldn't force you,
but you have to understand me.
I really have no other solutions.
I've been scared lately.
Just like when I was young,
I'm having nightmares every night.
I'm afraid that when I open my eyes,
you'll be gone.
I can't ask you
and I don't dare to ask.
I haven't been this afraid
in a long time.
I know I'm losing control.
But I just...
I just want to grab onto something
with all my might.
I will come back.
No matter what happens,
I will come back to you.
I will always be with you.
I promised you.
Why do you
cry so much now?
I don't.
♫Too many old dreams♫
♫Where did the snow fall to?♫
♫Going to face a catastrophe♫
♫No one is irrelevant♫
Ji Tanyin,
you're the Mute Lady of Wu Mountain.
♫A slight ripple in my gaze♫
You're someone that many people
♫Who knows the warmth and cold of my fleeting life?♫
worship like a god.
You must
keep your promise.
♫If staying together is difficult, it's not worth it♫
Since you've said
♫I'll return what's left of my life♫
you'll stay with me,
then you must always stay with me.
Since you've said
♫Falling into the mortal world♫
you will stay by my side,
♫Wandering through the clouds and rivers♫
then you must always
stay by my side.
♫Being by your side is like finding the shore♫
I'm also a good family's son.
♫If between oaths♫
I've fought on the battlefield for the human race
♫I hold onto the longing for just one more glance♫
and Youhu Clan.
♫Unwilling to bid farewell for good♫
I've charged in battle
and achieved merits.
♫Tears grow cold in a single cup♫
You can't
be like a swindler
♫Longing fades in half♫
and run away after taking advantage of me.
♫Like flowers in a mirror, or the moon in the water♫
Who's a swindler?
♫A thousand years of long nights, yearning from dawn to dusk♫
Tanyin,
what I said today
was not out of impulse.
I've thought about
♫A slight ripple in my gaze♫
this matter for a long time.
♫Who knows the warmth and cold of my fleeting life?♫
Today was just
coincidental timing.
That day on the tower of Yandu City,
♫If staying together is difficult, it's not worth it♫
I wanted to destroy the world.
♫I'll return what's left of my life♫
You were the one who stopped me.
From then on,
I've made up my mind.
♫Falling into the mortal world♫
♫Wandering through the clouds and rivers♫
I must
be with you for this lifetime.
♫Being by your side is like finding the shore♫
I want you to be my wife.
♫The moon falls by the riverbank♫
No one
♫The light finally dims♫
and nothing
♫How can my heart be at ease?♫
can change this.
Even you
♫Tears grow cold in a single cup♫
can't.
♫Longing fades in half♫
♫Like flowers in a mirror, or the moon in the water♫
So...
♫The lonely guest can't sleep, destiny can't be undone; speechless♫
Will you marry me?
I will love you well,
respect you,
♫Falling into the mortal world♫
and care for you.
♫Wandering through the clouds and rivers♫
You will be my priority
♫Being by your side is like finding the shore♫
and I'll always think for you.
You have to promise me.
♫The moon falls by the riverbank♫
Even if you guide me after death,
♫The light finally dims♫
you must do it completely.
♫How can my heart be at ease?♫
♫Tears grow cold in a single cup♫
♫Longing fades in half♫
♫Like flowers in a mirror, or the moon in the water♫
♫The lonely guest can't sleep, destiny can't be undone; speechless♫
Your handwriting is good.
Look at mine.
How is it?
Show her.
Ji Tanyin.
What do you think of my calligraphy?
♫Listening♫
♫Toona leaves knock fireflies into a vase♫
What's wrong?
We don't need your help
for this type of matter.
♫Ripples faintly spreading♫
We can do it ourselves.
I'm happy. I want to help.
♫In the pavilion in the clouds♫
♫Warm wine brews to the sound of the zither♫
After you get married,
♫The fragrance lingers like brush strokes, sketching out your form♫
will you finally leave?
Dream on.
♫Tonight♫
What does that mean?
♫In a light intoxication, I feel the longing in the crystalline snow♫
Tell me, what does that mean?
It means "no way."
♫I cannot bear to think of you♫
Tanyin, look.
♫I only wish♫
No,
I'm busy making wedding pastries.
♫That the years would remain ever sunny♫
Look!
See if my papercutting is pretty.
♫So that, within the drifting light, I could share the breeze with you♫
Not pretty.
No?
♫The wind blows♫
I think it's pretty.
♫It stirs the scenery♫
Why don't you teach me?
♫It awakens our heart♫
Let's cut it together.
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
I told you
I'll make wedding pastries and you do papercutting.
Don't bother me.
♫The closer we get♫
You...
You won't accompany me?
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
I won't.
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
Then
I'll stay here
to make wedding pastries with you.
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
No.
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It stirs the scenery♫
♫It awakens our heart♫
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
♫The closer we get♫
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
Yuanzhong.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
There must be something.
What happened?
I saw you in my dream.
You were wearing this
and looked so scary.
In the dream…
Dreams show opposite things.
The scarier I was in the dream,
the happier I'll be in reality.
Did I kiss you
in the dream?
So,
that wasn't the real me.
Are you still afraid?
Barrier?
Someone is coming.